# Charlie Cochrane

## Software Engineer / Team Leader

Website: ccochrane.com Github: github.com/charlesworth

Email: cochrane26@gmail.com

#### Profile

I'm a creative engineer and team leader with a wide variety of experience. I'm obsessed with software and computing, it's my life's passion (so far!). I enjoy building and empowering teams, shipping quality products and solving grand engineering challenges. I'm a lover of learning with a strong team ethic, I enable hiring, mentorship, education and career development.

#### Employment History

#### Independent Game Developer

2021-????

Founded Crooks Peak Limited, my VR game studio. Determined to not miss another tech shift, I've jumped head first into the VR gaming market. I love the mix of technical knowledge, creativity and pragmatism VR development requires.

Automata 2018-2020

Automata is a startup focused on bringing a disruptive robotic arm to market. I joined as an experienced hire to help scale and lead the engineering team and work full stack on the robot's internal control software and on Choreograph, it's 3D web based control platform. A fantastic mix of engineering challenge, leadership and customer work for a growing company.

Pusher 2017-2018

Pusher is a realtime communications API startup. I joined to experience a smaller team and have more responsibility across a product. Began on their data pipeline and later joined a new product team to design and launch Chatkit, a rich chat API service. Lots of great mentor and educator experiences here where I came into my own as a team leader.

IBM 2013-2016

Worked on IBM's container registry and cloud hosting service, Bluemix, helping to design, create and run the service. Lots of hard-learned lessons in running critical B2B infrastructure at scale. Previously worked on their Cloud Foundry app hosting service and consulted closely with large clients. An excellent early learning experience that built my confidence in shipping.

Intel 2011-2012

13 month placement working with Intel's customers on hardware, software and manufacturing quality.

### 131 Commando Royal Engineers

2009-2011

Trained Soldier and B3 Combat Engineer in the British Territorial Army.

#### Qualifications

Plymouth University: BEng Robotics

2009 - 2013

Received a 2:1 with honours. Included modules of programming, hardware design, electronics and robotics.

## Leadership Style

- Take responsibility, not power
- Early focus on culture

- Maximise transparency
- Foster confidence and leadership

## Skills and Knowledge

Languages: Mainly using Go, JS, Typescript, Python and C# most recently, but consider myself a generalist.

Infrastructure: Wide experience, from working with public cloud to updating customer deployed embedded devices.

**Shipping:** Experienced at confidently shipping new products and supporting existing projects.

Customer focus: I love working with customers, internal and external, to deliver value and set realistic expectations.

Best Practices: Refocusing team culture to embrace best practices and championing internal education and standards.